Guide to the Cornell University Laboratory of Ornithology artwork.
Cornell University Laboratory of Ornithology artwork.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University Laboratory of Ornithology artwork,
17-2-3522
Cornell University. Laboratory of Ornithology
.7 cubic ft.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Artwork on deposit from the Lab of Ornithology. Includes works by George Miksch Sutton, Anna Botsford Comstock, Mark Catesby and others.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Artwork on deposit from the Lab of Ornithology. Includes works by George Miksch Sutton, Anna Botsford Comstock, John Gould, and others.
John James Audubon, Louis Agassiz Fuertes and John Gould art work on deposit for the Lab has been added to the illustrators' corresponding collections.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University. Laboratory of Ornithology.; Bishop, Richard E. (Richard Evett), 1887-; Catesby, Mark, 1683-1749.; Comstock, Anna Botsford, 1854-1930.; Dilger, William C.; Horsfall, R. Bruce (Robert Bruce), 1869-1948; Kuroda, Nagahisa, 1916-; Leberman, Robert C.; Malick, Donald L.; Schaldach, William Joseph, 1896-.; Sutton, George Miksch, 1898-; Weick, Friedhelm.
Subjects:
Ornithology.; Ornithological illustration.; Birds in art.
Form/genre terms:
Drawings.; Paintings.; Etchings.; Watercolors.; Lithographs.; Hand coloring.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
By appointment only.
Items with four digit numbers can be identified using the Lab of Ornithology art database.
RELATED MATERIAL
The John James Audubon artwork, #6721, the Louis Agassiz Fuertes papers, #2662, and the John Gould Artwork Collection, #4736 also contain materials on deposit from the Laboratory of Ornithology
CONTAINER LIST
- George M. Sutton: Piping plover and Brown Pelicans (framed) (Box 1)
  Black and White Drawings
- George M. Sutton: Seed Snipe (Grey-breasted Snipe), 2971 (Box 1)
  Painting
- George M. Sutton: Ivory-billed Woodpecker, 2976 (Box 1)
  Color painting and print
- George M. Sutton: Ruddy Turnstone, 2978, July 28, 1969 (Box 1)
  Watercolor on board
- George M. Sutton: American Finfoot (Sungrebe), 2979 (Box 1)
  Watercolor on board with pecil sketches on the reverse
- George M. Sutton: Common Eider, 2980 (Box 1)
  Watercolor on paper
- George M. Sutton: "John Ell Drying His Mitts Over the Koodilik Flame", 2982, 1929 (Box 1)
  Ink on paper
- George M. Sutton: Turkey Vulture, 2983, July 13, 1948 (Box 1)
- George M. Sutton: Baltimore Orioles, 2984 (Box 1)
- George M. Sutton: Vesper Sparrows, 2986, August 14, 1940 (Box 1)
- George M. Sutton: Music "Early Evening" by Sutton with Christmas card. (Box 1)
- George M. Sutton: Ivory-billed Woodpeckers, 2981 (Box 3)
- Andrew Berger and Kenneth Prescott: Cerulean Warbler, 0260, 1948 (Box 2)
- Robert C. Leberman: Unnamed bird, 0700 (Box 2)
  Pencil on Paper. Has hand written label, presumably from Fisk that says "Drawn for me by Robert C. Leberman of Carnegie Museum." Mounted to a letter sent by Leberman to Fisk.
- Diane Pierce: Golden Eagle Chick, 2593, 1977 (Box 2)
  Pencil on paper
- Robert Horsfall: Northern Shoveler, 6368 (Box 2)
- Richard Bishop: Snow Geese, 5109 (Box 2)
- Anna Comstock: Butterfly (Moth), 8070, 1891 (Box 2)
  Engraving
- Nagahisa Kuroda: Crested Shelduck, 0610, 1978 (Box 2)
  Watercolor on paper. Matted and glued to foam board
- William J. Schaldach: American Woodcock, 1750, 1936 (Box 2)
  Oil on board
- William J. Schaldach: Ruffed Grouse, 1751, 1936 (Box 2)
  Print on paper. "Portrait of a Gentleman"
- George Edwards: Wattled Jacana, 0612, 1760 (Box 2)
  Lithograph on paper. "The fourth Brasilian Water-Hen of Marcgrave, drawn from life by G. Edwards; original is the property of John Fothergill, M.D. of London
- William Dilger: White-bearded Manakin, 2100 (Box 2)
- Donald Malick: Green Kingfisher, 2501 (Box 2)
- J Mark Catesby: "Ardea Stellaris" Green Heron, 0609 (Box 3)
  Lithograph on paper
- J Mark Catesby: "Ardea Alba" - Great Egret, 0613 (Box 3)
- W. Nayer: Ruff, 0611, 1778 (Box 3)
- Friedham Weick: Eurasion Hobbies, 3100, 1990 (Box 3)
  Watercolor
- Larry McQueen: Poster of common eastern feeder birds (Box 3)